Dorchester, Boston, Mass. Second Church records, 1770-1991.
Congregational Library Archives
Dorchester, Boston, Mass. Second Church records, 1770-1991.
RG0069
Congregational Library Archives
25.59 Cubic Feet
(33 cases)
The Second Church in Dorchester was first organized on January 1, 1808 by 64 members of First Church. The first official pastor for the newly formed Second Church was Dr. John Codman. Codman was a member of an influential family and graduated from Harvard. His pastorate continues to be the longest for the church and during this time was regularly visited by Daniel Webster and (on occasion) John Adams. The last pastor of Second Church in Dorchester was Reverend Donald P. Brickley. He facilitated the transfer of the church to the Church of the Nazarene in 1990. The Church of the Nazarene still exists today and carries with it the history of Second Church. The collection contains written material, finances, auxiliary organizations, incorporated churches, events, pastoral, legal and institutional records.
Second Church (Dorchester, Boston, Mass.)
Dorchester Central Congregational Church (Dorchester, Boston, Mass.)
Harvard Congregational Church (Dorchester, Boston, Mass.)
Codman, John, 1782-1847
Little, Arthur, Rev.
Pierce, Jason Noble, 1880-1948
Richards, Andrew, Rev.
Restrictions on Access
Access to this collection is unrestricted and open to the public.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Original collection was donated in 1963 and was not accessioned until it was converted into a gift in 1989. No accession number was given at the time. A second deposit of materials were gifted to the Congregational Library & Archives by Second Church of Dorchester in January 2019; accession number 2019-02.
Historical Note
The Second Church in Dorchester was first organized on January 1, 1808 by 64 members of First Church of Dorchester. These 64 members included 27 men and 37 women who had decided to split from the "Mother Church". On January 19, 1810 the group voted to name the new church South Church in Dorchester. This name only lasted two years when on April 3, 1812 they renamed the church "Second Church". The expansion into a new church was mainly meant to tackle the expanding population of the area. The first official pastor for the newly formed Second Church was Dr. John Codman. Codman was a member of an influential family and graduated from Harvard. His pastorate continues to be the longest for the church and during this time was regularly visited by Daniel Webster and (on occasion) John Adams. Reverend Codman would die on December 23, 1847. Before his death, he indicated to a fellow friend his intention to donate a field near the parish so that it would be a cemetery, Codman being its first occupant. The next year, Baker's Corner was officially named Codman Square. The next pastor was Reverend James H. Means who saw Second Church through the Civil War. Next was Reverend Edward N. Packard who facilitated that building of the parsonage. Following Packard was Reverend Arthur Little who organized the Chinese Sunday School as well as purchasing the church organ. The next pastor, Reverend Jason Noble Pierce would take the church through WW1. Second church had 203 men and women leave for the armed forces and Pierce would serve time as Senior Chaplain for the Second Division. Reverend Vaughn Dabney, taking over for Pierce, oversaw the formation of the official corporate "Second Church". He also oversaw the reuniting of Harvard Congregational back into Second Church. During WW2, Reverend Andrew Richards oversaw the parish as well as the 163 individuals who left to fight. Next, Reverend Frank T. Jensen would help oversee the reuniting of Central Congregational Church back to Second Church. Reverend Thomas G. Jones became the ninth pastor in 1979 and during his ministry the church celebrated the 175th anniversary in 1980. The last pastor of Second Church in Dorchester was Reverend Donald P. Brickley. He facilitated the transfer of the church to the Church of the Nazarene in 1990. The Church of the Nazarene still exists today and carries with it the history of Second Church.
List of Ministers
Rev. John Codman, D.D. 1808-1847
Rev. James Howard Means, D.D. 1848-1878
Rev. Edward N. Packard, D.D. 1879-1887
Rev. Arthur Little, D.D. 1889-1912
Pastor Emeritus 1912-1915
Rev. Jason Noble Pierce, D.D. 1914-1920
Rev. Vaughan Dabney, D.D. 1920-1931
Rev. Andrew Richards, D.D. 1932-1966
Rev. Frank T. Jensen, D.D. 1967-1979
Rev. Thomas G. Jones 1979-1984
Rev. Donald P. Brickley 1988-1990
Scope and Contents
This collection contains numerous items split up into multiple series and sub-series. Included in this are written materials such as correspondences and writings, legal information such as pew and court records, institutional records such as vital statistics and meeting minutes, financial information such as accounts and receipts, information on over two dozen auxiliary organizations, records for pastors across all of Second Church's history, records of Harvard Congregational Church and Central Congregational Church and finally records of events such as plays, anniversaries and picnics.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into 8 series and 81 sub-series, with each sub-series representing a different topic or individual. Within each sub-series the records are arranged chronologically.
Series 1: Written materials, 1770-1981
Sub-series 1: Correspondence, 1770-1981
Sub-series 2: Writings, 1806-1811, 1827, undated
Series 2: Legal, 1774-1987
Sub-series 1: Pew records, 1774-1925, 1969
Sub-series 2: Church land and construction, 1808-1929, 1966-1987
Sub-series 3: Court records, 1824, 1921-1931, 1974-1987
Sub-series 4: Estates and wills, 1923-1984
Series 3: Institutional records, 1805-1987
Sub-series 1: Vital statistics, 1805-1980
Sub-series 2: Meetings, 1806-1810, 1848-1967
Sub-series 3: Incorporation and by-laws, 1807-1986
Sub-series 4: Church records, 1807-1987
Sub-series 5: Publications, 1848-1995
Sub-series 6: Photos and phonographs, 1882-1883, 1955
Sub-series 7: Board of deacon's records, March 19, 1905 - September 22, 1984
Sub-series 8: Church committee records, 1918-1972
Sub-series 9: Board of trustees reports, 1921-1983
Sub-series 10: Annual reports, 1922, 1935, 1968-1987
Sub-series 11: Secretary reports, 1978-1987
Series 4: Finances, 1806-1989
Sub-series 1: Accounts, 1806-1988
Sub-series 2: Records, 1807-1837, 1867-1988
Sub-series 3: Receipts, 1820-1878, 1972
Sub-series 4: Treasurer, 1867-1986
Sub-series 5: Banking, 1904-1925, 1960-1987
Sub-series 6: Donations, 1925, 1960-1982
Sub-series 7: Weekly offerings, 1928, 1982-1989
Sub-series 8: Trust fund, 1946-1981
Sub-series 9: Quarterly returns, 1962-1971
Sub-series 10: Income, 1963-1988
Sub-series 11: Budgets, 1968-1986
Series 5: Auxiliary organizations, 1813-1984
Sub-series 1: Dorchester Female Benevolent Society, 1813-1855
Sub-series 2: Sunday School, 1818-1980
Sub-series 3: Sabbath School, 1820-1878, 1914-1933
Sub-series 4: Ladies Missionary Association, 1826-1871
Sub-series 5: Home Missionary Society, 1828-1832
Sub-series 6: Ladies Home Missionary Society, 1828-1899
Sub-series 7: Foreign Missionary Society, 1828-1867, 1930-1935
Sub-series 8: Maternal Association, 1851-1881
Sub-series 9: Dorchester Women's Missionary Society, 1870-1895
Sub-series 10: Social Bible Class, 1885
Sub-series 11: Young People's Society, 1886-1890
Sub-series 12: Codman Guild, 1893-1949
Sub-series 13: Dorcas Society, 1894-1915
Sub-series 14: Ladies Foreign Missionary Society, 1895-1909
Sub-series 15: Junior Christian Endeavor Society, 1897-1911
Sub-series 16: Young Ladies Missionary Society, 1898-1916
Sub-series 17: Music Department, 1898-1923
Sub-series 18: Women's Home Mission Auxiliary, 1899-1920
Sub-series 19: Baraca Class, 1905-1929
Sub-series 20: Chinese Sunday School, 1909, 1934-1935
Sub-series 21: Men's Club, 1909-1920
Sub-series 22: Codman Class, 1909-1951
Sub-series 23: Teacher's Club, 1911-1935
Sub-series 24: Philathea Class, 1912-1916
Sub-series 25: Dorchester Gentlemen's Driving Club, 1913-1915
Sub-series 26: Monday Missionary Society, 1916-1961
Sub-series 27: Boys' Brass Band, 1917-1920
Sub-series 28: Second Church Auxiliary, January 1918 - May 1922
Sub-series 29: Women's Association, 1922-1984
Sub-series 30: Bumpus Memorial Class, 1925-1932
Sub-series 31: Codman Glee Club, February 22-23, 1927
Sub-series 32: Phi Sigma Phi, 1928-1976
Sub-series 33: Couples Club, 1943-1953
Sub-series 34: Adult Fellowship, 1953-1957
Sub-series 35: Dorchester Women's Club, February 1963
Sub-series 36: Religious Education Committee, 1979-1981
Sub-series 37: Missionary Committee, 1981
Sub-series 38: NEPCO Senior Citizens, 1981-1982
Sub-series 39: Bible Club of Boston, undated
Sub-series 40: Mutual Admiration Society, undated
Series 6: Pastoral records, 1830-1982
Sub-series 1: Rev. Dr. John Codman, 1830-1839
Sub-series 2: Rev. James H. Means, 1848-1873
Sub-series 3: Records about other church pastors, 1868, 1952, 1967, 1982
Sub-series 4: Rev. Edward N. Packard, April 8, 1879
Sub-series 5: Rev. Arthur Little, 1888-1916
Sub-series 6: Reports and letters, 1896-1987
Sub-series 7: Rev. Jason Noble Pierce, 1914-1947
Sub-series 8: Rev. Vaughn Dabney, 1924-1929
Sub-series 9: Rev. Andrew Richards, 1926-1969
Sub-series 10: Rev. Frank T. Jensen, 1967-1968
Sub-series 11: Rev. Thomas G. Jones, 1978-1981
Series 7: Incorporated churches, 1888-1991
Sub-series 1: Harvard Congregational Church, 1888-1940, 1988-1991
Sub-series 2: Central Congregational Church, 1902-1973
Series 8: Events, 1900-1985
Technical Requirements
Edison Diamond Discs are available for viewing but are not available for playing due to their fragility. Talk to the archivist to find digital versions of the songs through YouTube.
Bibliography
"History." Second Church in Dorchester. March 23, 2019. Accessed June 24, 2019. http://secondchurchdorchester.org/about-us-2/history/.
Church records and registers.; Church finance.; Sunday schools -- Records.; Clergy -- Correspondence.; Church records and registers -- Massachusetts -- Dorchester.; Dorchester (Boston, Mass.) -- History.; Worship programs.; Community organization.; Photographs.; Christian education of children -- United States.; Education -- Massachusetts.; Second Church (Dorchester, Boston, Mass.); Dorchester Central Congregational Church (Dorchester, Boston, Mass.); Harvard Congregational Church (Dorchester, Boston, Mass.); Codman, John, 1782-1847; Little, Arthur, Rev.; Pierce, Jason Noble, 1880-1948; Richards, Andrew, Rev.
- Written material, 1770 1981; 1770-1981; 19 Items
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains written material such as correspondences and writings.
  - Correspondence, 1770 1981; 1770-1981; 16 Items
    This sub-series contains letters and correspondences from and adressed to Second Congregational Church in Dorchester.
    - Letters, 1770 1856; 1770-1856 (Box 28, Folder 44)
    - Letters, 1834 1919; 1834-1919 (Box 28, Folder 49)
    - Sympathy Letters after Church Fire (1 of 4), 1908-01 (Box 28, Folder 45)
    - Sympathy Letters after Church Fire (2 of 4), 1908-01 (Box 28, Folder 46)
    - Sympathy Letters after Church Fire (3 of 4), 1908-01 (Box 28, Folder 47)
    - Sympathy Letters after Church Fire (4 of 4), 1908-01 (Box 28, Folder 48)
    - Centennial Celebration letters, 1908 (Box 28, Folder 50)
    - Correspondences, 1924 (Box 28, Folder 56)
    - Correspondences, 1925 (Box 28, Folder 57)
    - Trustees' letters, 1925 1928; 1925-1928 (Box 28, Folder 51)
    - Correspondences, 1929 1981; 1929, 1981 (Box 28, Folder 58)
    - Caudle Cup Correspondences, 1932 1933; 1932-1933 (Box 28, Folder 59)
    - Janet Robinson Letters and Appreciation Guest Book, 1942 1959; 1942-1959 (Box 28, Folder 52)
    - Letters, 1944 (Box 28, Folder 53)
    - Letters from "Brownie" to Janet Robertson, 1957 (Box 28, Folder 54)
    - Send to Mr.Kendall..., undated (Box 28, Folder 55)
  - Writings, 1806 1827; 1806-1811, 1827, undated; 3 Items
    This sub-series contains individual writings of Hannah Lewis, a Poem by Hannah Robinson for her daughters and a Burlesque upon the Annual Ordination Celebration of the Church.
    - Hannah Lewis' writings, 1806 1811; 1806-1811 (Box 11, Volume 1)
    - A Poem by Hannah Robinson for her daughters, January 9, 1827 (Box 25, Folder 79)
    - A Burlesque upon the Annual Ordination Celebration of the Church, undated (Box 25, Folder 80)
- Legal, 1774 1987; 1774-1987; 64 Items
  This series contains legal information such as pew records, church land and construction, court records, estates and wills.
  - Pew records, 1774 1969; 1774-1925, 1969; 25 Items
    This sub-series contains deeds, plans, rentals and correspondences related to Second Churches pews.
    - Pews, Deeds and Actions, 1774 1818; 1774-1818 (Box 25, Folder 66)
    - Plan of Original Pews, 1805 (Box 25, Folder 67)
    - Pew Plans with Names, 1805 1806; 1805-1806 (Box 25, Folder 68)
    - Original Pew Assignments, 1806 (Box 25, Folder 69)
    - Pews, Deeds and Actions, 1808 1847; 1808-1847 (Box 25, Folder 70)
    - Pews Index and Deeds, 1833 1858; 1833-1858 (Box 16, Volume 3)
    - Pew Information, 1838 1879; 1838-1879 (Box 16, Volume 4)
    - Pew Deeds 1-52, 1854 1925; 1854-1925 (Box 25, Folder 71)
    - Pew Deeds 56-98, 1854 1925; 1854-1925 (Box 25, Folder 72)
    - Pew Deeds 105-139, 1854 1925; 1854-1925 (Box 25, Folder 73)
    - Pew Correspondences, 1860 1969; 1860, 1871, 1969 (Box 31, Folder 62)
    - Pew and Shed Information, 1878 1898; 1878-1898 (Box 16, Volume 5)
    - Pew Information, 1890 1894; 1890-1894 (Box 16, Volume 6)
    - Pew Information, 1900 1903; 1900-1903 (Box 16, Volume 7)
    - Pew records, 1902 1919; 1902-1919 (Box 3, Volume 2)
    - Pew Assessment and Applications, 1911 (Box 31, Folder 63)
    - Pew Information, 1916 1919; 1916-1919 (Box 16, Volume 8)
    - Letter Authorizing Change in Valuation of Pews, 1917-03-21 (Box 25, Folder 75)
    - Assessment of Pews, 1917-03 (Box 25, Folder 74)
    - Old vs. New Valuation of Pews, February 23, 1918 (Box 31, Folder 64)
    - Pew Information, 1920 1923; 1920-1923 (Box 16, Volume 9)
    - Blank Pew Deeds, 1922 (Box 25, Folder 76)
    - Pew Rentals Financial Ledger, 1922 1925; 1922-1925 (Box 19, Volume 3)
    - Pew Assignments, undated (Box 25, Folder 77)
    - Proposed Re-adjustment of the Valuation and Assessment of the Pews, undated (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Church land and construction, 1808 1987; 1808-1929, 1966-1987; 23 Items
    This sub-series contains information related to church lands and construction projects. Examples include the Parish House building fund, purchasing of a new organ, contracts for projects and valuation of the parsonage.
    - Quitclaim Deed, May 9, 1808 (Box 29, Folder 35)
    - Proprietors of the South meeting House, 1808 1814; 1808, 1814 (Box 25, Folder 15)
    - Selling Land, 1854 (Box 25, Folder 33)
    - Papers relating to a new organ, 1857 (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - Shed Deed, 1858 (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - Parish House Building Fund, 1922 1930; 1922-1930 (Box 28, Folder 62)
    - Land Registration Matters, 1922 1941; 1922-1941 (Box 24, Folder 11)
    - Parish House records, 1924 1925; 1924-1925 (Box 27, Folder 44)
    - Parish House Building Fund, 1924 1936; 1924-1936 (Box 20, Volume 19)
    - Report of Special Insurance Committee, 1928 1929; 1928-1929 (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - Contract with A. Piotti Company, June 1, 1929 (Box 28, Folder 63)
    - Parsonage Renovation, 1966 (Box 29, Folder 9)
    - Boiler Inspection Report, September 19, 1967 (Box 28, Folder 37)
    - Work Quotes, 1968 (Box 28, Folder 67)
    - Plan of Pasture Lands, May 12, 1970 (Box 25, Folder 78)
    - Parsonage Property Valuation, 1979 (Box 29, Folder 10)
    - Property Insurance, 1980 1982; 1980-1982 (Box 29, Folder 11)
    - Roofing Repairs, 1982 1987; 1982-1987 (Box 29, Folder 12)
    - Land Sale, June 4 (Box 25, Folder 48)
    - Estimates from Parkhurst Building Company, undated (Box 29, Folder 71)
    - Ministerial Lands, undated (Box 29, Folder 14)
    - Parish House Subscription List, undated (Box 28, Folder 22)
    - Shed Ownership, undated (Box 29, Folder 13)
  - Court records, 1824 1987; 1824, 1921-1931, 1974-1987; 8 Items
    This sub-series contains legal information related to the Second Church of Dorchester. Includes the Suffolk Superior Court, Probate court and Boston's Board of Appeals.
    - Letter from John Lowell to Codman, esquire Regarding Vans Suit, March 10, 1824 (Box 25, Folder 17)
    - Probate Court, 1921 (Box 30, Folder 14)
    - City of Boston's Board of Appeals Decision, October 3, 1924 (Box 25, Folder 24)
    - Letters related to land court, 1930 1931; 1930-1931 (Box 30, Folder 15)
    - Court Case Records on Checks Paid, 1974 1986; 1974-1986 (Box 30, Folder 16)
    - Court Order for Paperwork, 1987-02 1987-03; February - March 1987 (Box 30, Folder 17)
    - Suffolk Superior Court Complaints and Orders, 1987 (Box 30, Folder 18)
    - Court Case Corespondences, 1984 1987; 1984-1987 (Box 25, Folder 26)
  - Estates and wills, 1923 1984; 1923-1984; 8 Items
    This sub-series contains wills, estates and bequeathes related to the Second Church.
    - Will of Jacob J. Arakelyan, 1923 1925; 1923, 1925 (Box 25, Folder 39)
    - Wills, 1924, undated (Box 25, Folder 40)
    - Estates and Wills, 1938 1957; 1938-1957 (Box 29, Folder 36)
    - Flora Tarbell-Gardner Will, 1948 1951; 1948-1951 (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Estate of Alice S. Pearson, 1949 1950; 1949-1950 (Box 29, Folder 37)
    - Ellen M. Karcher's Will (copy), May 11, 1959 (Box 25, Folder 42)
    - Wills and Bequeaths, 1959 1971; 1959-1971 (Box 29, Folder 38)
    - Wills, 1980 1984; 1980-1984 (Box 25, Folder 47)
- Institutional records, 1805 1987; 1805-1987; 232 Items
  This series contains institutional records such as vital statistics, meetings, incorporation and by-laws, church records, publications, photos, Board of Deacon and church committee records, annual and secretary reports.
  - Vital statistics, 1805 1980; 1805-1980; 51 Items
    This sub-series contains information on vital statistics such as memberships, baptisms, marriages, and deaths.
    - Hymn Sung at Wedding of Stephen Robinson and Hannah Withington, April 11, 1805 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Membership Cards, 1808 1968; 1808-1968 (Box 28, Folder 14)
    - Marriages and Funerals, 1809 1953; 1809-1953 (Box 1, Volume 3)
    - An Act Relating to the Second Parish Cemetary, May 9, 1867 (Box 25, Folder 22)
    - Dismissions and Church Councils A-C, 1878-10 1896-01; October 1878 - January 1896 (Box 26, Folder 16)
    - Dismissions and Church Councils C-G, 1878-10 1896-01; October 1878 - January 1896 (Box 26, Folder 17)
    - Dismissions and Church Councils H-M, 1878-10 1896-01; October 1878 - January 1896 (Box 26, Folder 18)
    - Dismissions and Church Councils M-R, 1878-10 1896-01; October 1878 - January 1896 (Box 26, Folder 19)
    - Dismissions and Church Councils S-T, 1878-10 1896-01; October 1878 - January 1896 (Box 26, Folder 20)
    - Dismissions and Church Councils T-Z, 1878-10 1896-01; October 1878 - January 1896 (Box 26, Folder 21)
    - Membership, 1881 1931; 1881-1931 (Box 18, Volume 1)
    - Directories, 1890 1915; 1890-1915 (Box 28, Folder 25)
    - Second Parish Cemetary Journal, 1892 1940; 1892-1940 (Box 17, Volume 3)
    - Marriage Certificates, 1893 1914; 1893-1914 (Box 28, Folder 9)
    - Dismission and Church Council Index A-C, 1896-01-01 1903-12-31; January 1, 1896 - December 31, 1903 (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Dismissions and Church Council Index D-I, 1896-01-01 1903-12-31; January 1, 1896 - December 31, 1903 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Dismissions and Church Council Index J-N, 1896-01-01 1903-12-31; January 1, 1896 - December 31, 1903 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Dismissions and Church Council Index O-S, 1896-01-01 1903-12-31; January 1, 1896 - December 31, 1903 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Dismissions and Church Council Index T-Z, 1896-01-01 1903-12-31; January 1, 1896 - December 31, 1903 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Vital Statistics, 1900 1920; 1900-1920 (Box 15, Volume 8)
    - Membership Records (1 of 2), 1900 1986; 1900-1986 (Box 15, Volume 9)
    - Membership Records (2 of 2), 1900 1986; 1900-1986 (Box 15, Volume 10)
    - Dismissions and Church Councils A-C, 1904-01-01 1912-12-31; January 1, 1904 - December 31, 1912 (Box 26, Folder 22)
    - Dismissions and Church Councils C-G, 1904-01-01 1912-12-31; January 1, 1904 - December 31, 1912 (Box 26, Folder 23)
    - Dismissions and Church Councils G-L, 1904-01-01 1912-12-31; January 1, 1904 - December 31, 1912 (Box 26, Folder 24)
    - Dismissions and Church Councils L-M, 1904-01-01 1912-12-31; January 1, 1904 - December 31, 1912 (Box 26, Folder 25)
    - Dismissions and Church Councils M-S, 1904-01-01 1912-12-31; January 1, 1904 - December 31, 1912 (Box 26, Folder 26)
    - Dismissions and Church Councils T-Z, 1904-01-01 1912-12-31; January 1, 1904 - December 31, 1912 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Vital Statistics, 1906 1926; 1906-1926 (Box 18, Volume 5)
    - Members, April 1, 1910 (Box 28, Folder 28)
    - Applications for Membership in Second Church, 1911 (Box 28, Folder 20)
    - Membership and Church Councils A-C, 1913-01 1918; January 1913 - 1918 (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - Membership and Church Councils D-L, 1913-01 1918; January 1913 - 1918 (Box 27, Folder 10)
    - Membership and Church Councils M-R, 1913-01 1918; January 1913 - 1918 (Box 27, Folder 11)
    - Membership and Church Councils S-Z, 1913-01 1918; January 1913 - 1918 (Box 27, Folder 12)
    - Baptisms, 1914 1919; 1914-1919 (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - Baptism Certificate of Helen Isabel Ellis, December 16, 1915 (Box 27, Folder 38)
    - Membership, 1916 1922; 1916-1922 (Box 18, Volume 2)
    - Transfers and Dismissions, 1918 1922; 1918-1922 (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - Vital Statistics, 1922 1948; 1922-1948 (Box 18, Volume 6)
    - Membership, 1922 1987; 1922-1987 (Box 18, Volume 3)
    - Membership Cards, 1932 (Box 28, Folder 21)
    - Membership, 1932 1933; 1932-1933 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Codman Cemetary, 1942 1955; 1942-1955 (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Marriages and Funerals, 1953 1986; 1953-1986 (Box 3, Volume 1)
    - Funeral Service for Charlotte Beath Brown, 1980-05-20 (Box 28, Folder 36)
    - Church Membership, undated (Box 3, Volume 3)
    - Membership, undated (Box 18, Volume 4)
    - Membership Lists, undated (Box 27, Folder 26)
    - Baptism Certificate Example, undated (Box 27, Folder 37)
    - Helen Gertrude Hallgren application, undated (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - Meetings, 1806 1967; 1806-1810, 1848-1967; 18 Items
    This sub-series contains information on parish meetings, special meetings, annual meeting minutes.
    - Second Parish Meeting Minutes, 1806-11-06 1810-06; November 6, 1806 - June 1810 (Box 27, Folder 35)
    - Second Parish Meeting Attendance, 1807 1808; 1807-1808 (Box 25, Folder 14)
    - Ladies of the Second Church Meetings, 1848 1854; 1848, 1854 (Box 27, Folder 40)
    - Notice of First Meeting (duplicate), March 7, 1887 (Box 25, Folder 18)
    - Special Meeting Called, 1888-09-22 (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Special Meeting Called, 1888-12-03 (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - Church meeting minutes, 1888 1923; 1888-1923 (Box 16, Volume 2)
    - Warrants for Parish Meeting, 1898 1917; 1898-1917 (Box 25, Folder 20)
    - Warrant for Annual Meeting, 1904 1914; 1904, 1914 (Box 25, Folder 21)
    - Parish Meeting Minutes, 1914-02 1925-04; February 1914 - April 1925 (Box 14, Volume 1)
    - Call to Meeting, 1916-02-15 1916-02-23; February 15 - 23, 1916 (Box 27, Folder 33)
    - Warrant Notices, March 10, 1920 (Box 27, Folder 25)
    - Notice of Annual Meetings, February 9, 1921 (Box 27, Folder 39)
    - Special Corporate Meeting, March 13, 1924 (Box 27, Folder 42)
    - Motions for Meeting Prior to July 1, 1924, undated (Box 25, Folder 28)
    - Regular Corporate Meeting, November 21, 1924 (Box 27, Folder 43)
    - Minutes of Annual Meeting, 1958 1967; 1958-1967 (Box 27, Folder 36)